<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cindy Juarez</title>
    <description>Cindy Juarez (sceendy) is a front-end web developer based in Dallas, Texas.
</description>
    <link>http://sceendy.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sceendy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 10:11:48 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 10:11:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>quick look @ stocks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have developed an interest in economics and finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new found interest has led me to pick up the d3.js library to generate charts based on user input with a focus on personal finance and budgeting. However, I really wanted to design/build a ‘quick look at stocks’ widget for myself as well. I opened up CodePen and threw together a quick prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a super simple user interface that allows users to select from a list of companies to check their low/high stock value for the day along with the current value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&quot;250&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;//codepen.io/sceendy/embed/NNwzad/?height=250&amp;amp;theme-id=11022&amp;amp;default-tab=result&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/sceendy/pen/NNwzad/&quot;&gt; stock info&lt;/a&gt; by Cindy Juarez (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/sceendy&quot;&gt;@sceendy&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 05:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2016/04/27/quick-look-stocks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2016/04/27/quick-look-stocks.html</guid>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>api</category>
        
        <category>widget</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>hello seattle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, I decided to spend my birthday in Seattle. Last year, I spent my birthday in New York City - so, this year it felt right to spend it on the other coast. I have nothing against San Francisco but Seattle just called out to me more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These trips have just been 3 day weekends so my boyfriend and I are constantly on the move during our stay. Perhaps, it also helps distract me from my quarter-life crisis moment I have experienced for about 5 minutes during every birthday since I turned 21. Being up in the sky on the anniversary of my birth is actually quite nice and humbling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seattle is incredibly beautiful and fun with some of the best coffee, scenic views, and food I have tasted in the US. This is not about the trip, though. I just wanted to post on of my favorite pictures that I took. &lt;span class=&quot;text-pink&quot;&gt;#nofilter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hello-seattle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;seattle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 14:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2016/04/01/hello-seattle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2016/04/01/hello-seattle.html</guid>
        
        <category>birthday</category>
        
        <category>traveling</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>building a chrome extension</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past couple of months, I’ve been focused on building a personal project on the side. At some point, I realized that I could build a Chrome Extension as a tool to be utilized for this app so hey, why not learn a bit about the chrome.* APIs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, let me say, it is some very well written documentation that you will appreciate. Right away, the docs tell you all the basic files you need and give you some boilerplate code to get started. Also included are some downloadable examples that vary in complexity. It will be helpful if you are already familiar with HTML/CSS/JavaScript, btw. Within the hour, I had a functional extension and wanted to share how to get started on your own:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/chrome-extension_sm.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chrome Extension&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project, let’s make a Chrome Extension that can help you bookmark locations you want to visit which you will store for future use. Later you can hook it up to be sent to your database you have or some sort of Firebase-y service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, call in Chromes’ API to grab some basic info from the page. In this case, you want the title of the page which is often the name of the location and the URL so you can visit the site again if you need to which will be using the Chrome Tabs API. These items will be pre-filled into the form on the popup for your extension as seen above as soon as you click on your logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll keep your popup-specific JS in a file named popup.js and then your JS related to the page itself will be named content.js. It’s important that you keep these &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.chrome.com/extensions/content_scripts&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;separate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;//jsfiddle.net/sceendy/qrg0Lrx9/embedded/js,html/dark/&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to keep in mind while building a Chrome Extension is that you &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.chrome.com/extensions/contentSecurityPolicy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;can’t add inline JS to the HTML document&lt;/a&gt; (for security reasons). For instance, you will see I am adding an event listener to the &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;addAddressBtn&lt;/span&gt; element to make it clickable. Moving along, we will be using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.chrome.com/extensions/tabs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chrome Tabs API&lt;/a&gt; to interact with the browser tabs – this is for querying ‘tabs’ and assigning the url and title to variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, we store the value of the current tabs’ title to place into the &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;#page-title&lt;/span&gt; field and the url into the &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;#page-url&lt;/span&gt; field. Boom, half done. Now, let’s get into passing messages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we want to allow the user to select the address text of the location and once they have our extension popup open, they will find that they can easily paste it into the Address field. Since there is no real pattern online for mailing addresses, this is how we will handle it for our extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;//jsfiddle.net/sceendy/m02kbt4a/embedded/js/dark/&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This function queries the Chrome Tabs API again, this time, we are passing messages between the extension and the content script. Below, the &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;content.js&lt;/span&gt; file here is listening (using &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;chrome.tabs.onMessage&lt;/span&gt;) for a message (JSON object) from the popup.js file (using &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;chrome.tabs.sendMessage&lt;/span&gt;)and then handles it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; src=&quot;//jsfiddle.net/sceendy/sb9v4m1a/embedded/js,html/dark/&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it gets the current selection in the window, it turns it into a string to be sent back to the popup and pasted onto the textarea field. Now, you have an extension that you can hook up to your choice of backend to store this information and view it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 14:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2016/03/18/creating-my-first-chrome-extension.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2016/03/18/creating-my-first-chrome-extension.html</guid>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>api</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am done with contracting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past 10 years, I have done a few side projects outside of my school work and full-time jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started when I was ~14 and I realized people were willing to pay me to make their Myspace layouts. I’m still not sure how I managed to be hired by several people to do that but hey, it was fun. I really enjoyed designing and learning to build things with some markup, CSS, and a sliver of JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout college, I also continued to take on these small projects where I learned about different approaches to projects and how to write better code and it was quite the bonus to be able to graduate debt-free too. I mean, I was going to be learning and writing code, anyway… so why not make some money, too?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my senior year, I was able to focus on *one client since they had a decent amount of work for me (a few hours a month) and they paid well enough for me to feel alright not taking on more clients. The work was fun… building a custom WordPress theme which I thought was great back then, haha. I had learned so much from a bunch of small projects where I was mostly given free-reign. This particular client trusted my knowledge/skills and I appreciate that a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, now, as I have found an incredibly enjoyable job where I can build something awesome and expand my skills, side money is much less appealing with the added stress that comes with it, and I have personal projects I am growing passionate about that I’d much rather focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I find that I don&#39;t enjoy the side work anymore. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind is fulfilled in my full-time work and a personal project. The money is not a motivating factor, either. I’m happy. It’s not worth doing if it’s not fun and I’m glad that’s an even an option for me. So, as of today, I will no longer be accepting new work. In addition, any on-going side work will be terminated in May of this year (which my current clients already know about.) I can refer some awesome devs that I have met, though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Added bonus, a screenshot  of one of my last Myspace layouts that I got paid for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/topleft.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Myspace Layout for Local band&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;So... I&#39;m glad I&#39;ve gotten significantly better since 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 08:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2016/02/16/done-with-contracting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2016/02/16/done-with-contracting.html</guid>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
        <category>freelancing</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Source Contribution</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I made an open source contribution. It was not my first and definitely not my last but it made me realize something about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all use libraries and tools that we did not build ourselves. Many of the ones I use tend to have more than 50 contributors. Often times, they are super organized with github issues, PR’s, labeling, etc. Aside from being super useful, they also &lt;em&gt;tend to&lt;/em&gt; be well-documented. It’s nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always held back from making pull requests from them because I find putting my code out there a bit intimidating. I mean, someone has to merge it, right? Someone has to be like, “Ok, this works and is not written terribly.” The gatekeepers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We experience this at our jobs but there’s a bit less pressure since companies have private repos… your website might suck and be slow but now on is able to directly comment the pull request you made that ruined everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past couple of days, I’ve been working with Hologram to generate a styleguide. I had used Sassdown before but Hologram seems to have gotten a decent amount of attention and is pretty similar to Sassdown so why not? I was testing the pages and was happy but I wanted to center the footer text that was being generated per the default footer template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having worked so long to document the CSS and get it display the content how I wanted, I was a bit tired of staring at it all. I added a &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;text-align: center;&lt;/span&gt; and refreshed. No big deal. While doing that, I went back to the code to see if perhaps I could apply the project footer class to it as well. That’s when I noticed a &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; that was not being closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, it’s optional now; thanks HTML5. But it didn’t seem intentional as none of the other code seemed to take advantage of optional tags. I figured the worst that could happen is some sort of reply like, “Oh, it was intentional; thanks, though!” I never encountered negative comments on Github so yes, that’s the worst I could imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, I have had more and more people looking over my code so a little bit of the intimidation has faded. Had I actively put my code out there, put my personal projects on Github, though… I may have aquired more knowledge about best practices at a better rate. Lately, that’s what I was wondering. So, this time around, when I saw something I could fix… &lt;em&gt;why not?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My advice to anyone start out is to not be scared of getting your code rejected. It will help you improve; we have all sucked. We are all always getting better. And sometimes, you’ll make a small fix to a cool project and you’ll get a cool button on your &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/trulia/hologram/pull/252&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/os-contribute-trulia.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 12:34:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2015/11/13/open-source-contribution.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2015/11/13/open-source-contribution.html</guid>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
        <category>html</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From AngularJS to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My personal website has had many faces over the years. Each version was built using new skills I was learning at the time. I went from a static site to building a custom WordPress theme to a single page application using AngularJS. Not only was it built with something new each time, my designing skills have luckily improved too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year ago or so, I tried out Jekyll in order avoid putting anymore time tweaking with my site. It actually went pretty well but that urge to have a reason to mess with it sat quietly within me. Finally, I decided I could make it a simple AngualrJS that could consume an API for blogging – that’s it. I really just wanted more practice and a reason to do it. Thus, the site became an AngularJS app for the second time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was pretty happy with it as it was but the build up of Trello cards for my personal site was a bit much. Ideas came to me throughout the week to improve/change it. The thing is - I’ll admit it - … now I have ideas outside of my personal site. I have projects I want to build that can be built using whatever framework I desire to practice doing anything. My site was always my online playground. The thing is, I can build anything and put it anywhere. Granted, it’ll probably just be a Github repo but nevertheless, it’s there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to Jekyll was pretty obvious to me. I wanted something that was easy to maintain and the fact that it’s easy to host it on Github pages is certainly an appealing plus!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 13:09:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2015/11/04/from-angularjs-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2015/11/04/from-angularjs-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        <category>angular</category>
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Burning out and refueling</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At agencies, especially with big clients, you get used to mostly working during the clients’ business hours + not taking work home with you. You can get spoiled by the work/life balance. Well, that has been my experience with agencies. However, at some point, I decided I really wanted to focus on a single product which is when I searched for a startup that was building a product.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;55+hrs/week? sure.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a leap back in March 2014, I applied for a frontend developer position for a local startup that had already raised a decent amount of an investment. The new hire would be the first dedicated frontend developer for the redesigned/rebuilt platform. You kind of get sucked into the product and environment. Being a team player and putting in the extra hours seems inevitable, honestly. Getting a phone call at 7am to update the logo before you leave your house to head to the office? No big deal, it’s for the sake of the &lt;i&gt;team&lt;/i&gt;, right?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Don’t get me wrong – I loved it. Diving deeper into coding and learning more about all aspects of building web applications becomes an addiction. However, what I hadn’t realized is that with it comes this thing called &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;burning out&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. One day you just kind of start to fill worn out mentally. You wonder if you’re really getting any better. Self-doubt settles in. Looking over the same batch of code for a year and a half. Building new features and fixing old hacky code is just your norm.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;ok. nevermind.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past 2 months, I’ve looked back on that time. Yes, it was fun. For that year in a half, my learning/self-improvement was on a fast-track. It just wears you down – especially when you only take two incredibly short vacations. Accumulating 320 hours of vacation and not making a dent into it is ridiculous. Why didn’t I use it up? Well, there was always &lt;i&gt;&lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/i&gt; due – I couldn’t find the right time to get away, really. Or at least that’s what I told myself. It was self-inflicted the first year and going into my second year, I felt the pressure to push through for the sake of the product. So, last week, I saw an opportunity.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-GNLD88of4U8/VgYLggzchYI/AAAAAAAAKUU/kSUdfsQDdeo/s900/camping.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;It&#39;s as if I refilled my tank of passion for code. &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Hhuiav1vkmE/VgYNOg5vkEI/AAAAAAAAKUg/msf_V_EdmK8/s250/grandcanyon.jpg&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot; /&gt;
For the first time, I felt I had time. To make the situation even better, my boyfriend did too. We quickly jumped onto &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roadtrippers.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Roadtrippers&lt;/a&gt; and researched a few places we wanted to see and packed our bags. We headed west with the ultimate destination being the Grand Canyon - a beautiful place neither of us had visited and desired to visit prior to either of us graduating college.  We camped in Albuquerque, New Mexico and at the Grand Canyon in Arizona. Those five days were the first days in the past two years that I cleared my mind of code.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I observed and explored the nature around me. Any internet access was mostly sharing an image on instagram, though. A few emails here and there. It feels good to have taken a break - as if I cleared a slate. Once I arrived home, I thought about how I felt and reflected on the opportunity to focus on things outside of code I enjoy doing. Returning to my terminal and my code editor feels nice and refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 17:13:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2015/09/25/burning-out-and-refueling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2015/09/25/burning-out-and-refueling.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing and the process #2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in Part #1, I first consider content and then look for design inspiration. Layout is typically where I sometimes struggle for print, honestly. I don’t like adding content for the sake of filling space and I want the layout to help with the hierarchy of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design - Cover&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I looked around at different infographics. I’ve seen plenty of them and the items are often in their own space. I opened up Sketch, set the size, and began adding elements. My first graphic to create was the main one on the front - a house built with just rectangles (very minimalistic.) A banner for the heading felt appropriate - it makes me think “festive announcement.” Once I had the text done, I began to create the custom icons. I already knew what would be served: margaritas, beer, and pork. Those three things have some very recognizable graphics to represent them, luckily. Sketch allows you to make them into reusable symbols which is perfect.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lwBOhMNcMpg/VfBDSdIE_ZI/AAAAAAAAJvQ/X_SpGaSo458/s800/Screen%2BShot%2B2015-09-09%2Bat%2B9.32.57%2BAM.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(Yeah, I got lazy with the naming…)&lt;br /&gt;
Once the icons were made, and I finished the cover, I was inspired for the back part of the invitation. Clean, thin lines for borders. Continued use of the theme colors for the rest of the icons. Lovely.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3qwO-4wlnac/VfBBw6rIExI/AAAAAAAAJvE/t9LCYcUQ_P4/s800/front-public.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design - Back&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to continue on with simple, thin-bordered rectangles, I decided to use them to divide the content for the back. I used a serif font for descriptive text which I barely used since most of them did not need descriptions. The sans-serif font was used for the information itself and the numbers were made a bit heavier that the regular text. The decorative font was really just used for the word “anniversary” for the cover but I found another use for it: our names. It didn’t make sense for either the sans-serif and serif fonts to be used for our names so using the display text was more of a “let’s see if this works” approach. Glad it worked out.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-RtNw-j_XtD4/Ve8Z3JT6dUI/AAAAAAAAJuM/CcjDOxBzg3Y/s800/invitation-back-design.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;small&gt;This is part two of a two part entry.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 04:42:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2015/09/09/designing-and-the-process-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2015/09/09/designing-and-the-process-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing and the process #1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For most of this year, I have been focused on improving my technical skills. No complaints; I love building single page applications. On the other hand, there have been times where I reach for a pencil and start to sketch.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My first job ever was a development/design position with a much greater emphasis on designing for print: flyers, posters, shirts, etc. I never thought much about my process or workflow, though. I would receive an assignment - often a poster for an event - and look at previous designs for the same event since most of the events were annual. Some would be pretty basic such as one graphic, a patterned background, and the necessary text. Others would have incredible details such as vector graphics and custom typography. I enjoyed looking through the variety as it was a student position so turnover was quick which left a range of previous work. Looking for inspiration? Well, upon reflection, I suppose I was looking for direction and would take my own lead from there.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now, though, I don’t do as much designing as I used to. Sure, I contribute to design like I did at Joinem… but more often than not, I stick to consulting by choice. I respect designers and their ability to create beautiful things from nothing. At Joinem, I felt like more of a lighthouse since we had various people touching the designs with no styleguide. I highly discourage that, by the way. &lt;b&gt;There is such a thing as too many cooks in a kitchen and sometimes they aren’t all cooks. &lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I felt compelled to create a dynamic styleguide for the team after a couple months of receiving a bunch of different font sizes and styles from freelance designers but rarely had the time to add to it. I was focused on the client-side code; so, there you have it, an important aspect of a website was a frontend developers’ side-project that was on the back-burner. How unfortunate. No, I don’t think that a styleguide would have solved all of our problems. It could have prevented a substantial amount and saved so much time/efforts, though.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, these days, I have the time to reengage with my creative side. A year ago, I bought a house with my boyfriend. A few months into it, I bought these blank cardboard-looking cards that I thought would be nice to design on. Eventually, I found a great use for them: invitations! They were a good 3.5 x 5.5 inches but figured I could make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these are invitations for my own events, I first write down the information that is needed such as location, time, date, etc. Then, I use that to begin the layout. The cards are relatively small so I aim to make the best use of the space. Luckily, they’re double sided so really one side can have all the &lt;i&gt;needed&lt;/i&gt; information and the other side can be the “fun” part for me. Once I have the layout, I continue on with the other aspects of the design.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I am incredibly picky about colors. These cards were a bit limiting in a way because they are quite dark. It kind of narrowed the scope for color. So, I started by visiting dribbble and looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/search?q=brown&quot;&gt;color palettes that had been used with brown&lt;/a&gt; (the color of the cards). I generally had a theme in my mind for the event itself but I had to determine if it needed to be lightened or darkened to look good on the card itself. A dark gray is always a beautiful color for text and it’d be pretty powerful on a brownish background so I chose it for my main text color. Light shades of red and blue worked well for large text (titles) and graphics.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-GaQRxwNx3XY/VenvnmYTd7I/AAAAAAAAJns/gqnlsvvYy4g/s900/designs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Invitation designs&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;The one on the left is the front of a birthday BBQ card and the one on the right is the back of the house anniversary card.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;This is part one of a two part entry.&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 09:44:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2015/09/04/designing-and-the-process-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2015/09/04/designing-and-the-process-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Code Challenge #7</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This weeks’ Code Challenge by DevWars is back to the basics. They provided a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/shots/2200506-Article-teaser-card&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;neat dribbble design&lt;/a&gt; and want us to code it out. Initially, the challenges were pretty static (i.e. here’s a design, use HTML/CSS to build it out) but this week, they want developers to show off some JavaScript and CSS3 skills. Bring forth the animations!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Objectives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make this card fold in half and “close”, like a book.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On hover it must open to show the content.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;BONUS&lt;/em&gt; Add some extra pages.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&quot;577&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;//codepen.io/sceendy/embed/NqZWNm/?height=577&amp;amp;theme-id=11022&amp;amp;default-tab=result&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/sceendy/pen/NqZWNm/&quot;&gt;DevWarsWeek7&lt;/a&gt; by Cindy Juarez (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/sceendy&quot;&gt;@sceendy&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;my approach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pretty much stuck to the design as it is but personalized it a little with my own photos/name and the date I worked on it. The challenge requirements seemed a bit odd to me, though - the interaction, anyway. Hovering to show the card? &lt;a href=&quot;http://uxmovement.com/navigation/why-hover-menus-do-users-more-harm-than-good/&quot;&gt;Bleh&lt;/a&gt; - not a fan of hovering when it means hiding &lt;i&gt;useful&lt;/i&gt; information rather than adding additional content (tips, etc). If it’s theoretically an article card, I’d imagine that it’d already be displaying - interactions should be added upon it; not to reveal it. Since it’s a teaser, it might be better to do that action for the &lt;b&gt;read more&lt;/b&gt; function instead.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As far as the code went, I debated on the best way to handle the skewed side of the left panel and doing most of the animation with CSS3. There were a few of ways I could imagine accomplishing this but in the end I went with a similar approach that I take with ribbons on cards.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;sass:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sass&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;:after
  content: &#39;&#39;
  height: 100%
  width: 90px
  background: #fff
  position: absolute
  top: 0
  right: -49px
  -webkit-transform: skew(10deg)
  -moz-transform: skew(10deg)
  -o-transform: skew(10deg)
  z-index: -9
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;css3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the skew method to get the side slanted like in the design. By adding the pseudo, &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;:after&lt;/span&gt; for &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;.left-side&lt;/span&gt; it becomes hooked onto that class. Next up were the animations, two classes were created: &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;.animation-in&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;.animation-out&lt;/span&gt; to toggle when the close button is clicked. I added &lt;span class=&quot;code-inline&quot;&gt;transform: scaleX(-1) translateX(-100px)&lt;/span&gt; to create the illusion of the page turning. It currently just flips the text too and my next step would be to make it show as more of a book cover at the midpoint before it completely flips. However, I do like doing these write ups right after I’ve worked on these challenges in the allotted time for my own learning purposes. Plus, it’s pretty cool looking back on these and seeing how much more efficient I become with tasks like this.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;The goal is to only spend 1-2 hours on these.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 09:06:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/2015/08/20/code-challenge-7.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/2015/08/20/code-challenge-7.html</guid>
        
        <category>css3</category>
        
        <category>sass</category>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
