<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cindy Juarez</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://sceendy.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sceendy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 21:32:24 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 21:32:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Goals for 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone born in 1990, I have always used the years divisible by 5 as checkpoints of my life. I think it started out as an easy way to keep track of my age or something trivial like that. Nevertheless, I use it as a time to evaluate myself and the things I have accomplished but more importantly, plan for the future. Not to say that I don’t do that as deemed necessary by myself between every 5 years but I think it allows for more perspective around this time.&lt;br /&gt;
I am currently quite happy with where I am - both in regards to my personal and professional life. In 2014, I bought a house by the lake and got a job as a front-end developer at a startup. I like to build upon every goal - there’s not really a finish line. That being said, I wanted to share my goals that are a bit specific to the year, though. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
GREAT PEOPLE DO GREAT THINGS… TOGETHER.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#1&lt;/strong&gt; - I want to continue improving as a team member. Prior to my current job, “developer teams” were typically more like partnerships. It involved myself and another developer double teaming a project by splitting the work right down the middle. However, now, I work with a few more developers on a tad bit more complex projects than I have before. They each have their strengths and come from different backgrounds so there are often some clashes of ideas. As the least experienced developer in the group, I sometimes would sit by and wait for them to work it out. Lately I have been more vocal and chimed in with opinions of my own which has really helped me develop more of a role. (Hey, I’m the only frontend developer in the group so I get a lot of chances to learn about the backend but the decision making is left to them.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#2&lt;/strong&gt; - Open source a WordPress starter template. I have been developing custom WordPress themes for a couple years now and I have really want to get into making my own starter responsive template. Considering how many different ones I looked at when I first started, I feel this is least I can do to give back to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 16:42:12 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/personal/2015/01/09/goals-for-2015.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/personal/2015/01/09/goals-for-2015.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Messing around with the Tumblr API</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid managing a blog myself, I wanted to try out handling my blogging with the Tumblr API. I figured it’d be easier to keep up with and leave out any complexity from integrating a blog onto my actual site. It’s easier just to hit up some API endpoints with ngResource since I’m using Angular.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This was actually the first time I set up a site to reach out to some API endpoints so I thought I could write a little about my experience.&lt;br /&gt;
Tumblr’s API documentation is quite simple to understand and allowed for me to get it all hooked up within an hour. I got an OAuth Key and then used Angulars’ ngResource to point to their API and get it to return the JSON.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;var url = &quot;http://api.tumblr.com/v2/blog/&quot;+ blog_url + &quot;/posts/text?api_key=&quot; + api_key + &#39;&amp;amp;limit=20&#39;;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I placed made the blog_url and api_key variables for better visibility and I am not sure if I will keep the URL of the Tumblr I have had since 2009. At the end of the line, I limited the amount of posts to grab to 20 for now to see how I like it. Of course, on the front-end of the home page, I limitTo 4 posts and on the archive page I let it reach the limit set in the URL.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Once I got that setup, I decide to make a little test in the console to make sure all was well.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;_resource.test(function(data, $sce){ console.log(&#39;Tumblr status = &#39;+ data.meta.status + &#39;, msg = &#39; + data.meta.msg + &#39; for &#39; + data.response.blog.title);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Which then returned the following:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://31.media.tumblr.com/a0eb63c50643de3c12acdd599b86d9fe/tumblr_inline_ngl2qsOSMD1qzntgb.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fantastic! That meant I was good to go ahead and call in some of the data.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;index.js:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;$scope.blog = data.response.posts;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;page.html:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div ng-repeat=&quot;blog in blog | limitTo : 4&quot;&amp;gt; /* grab up to 4 blog entries and repeat the data*/&lt;br /&gt; /* so this returns data.response.posts.title */&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 10:46:30 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/angular/api/code/2014/12/17/messing-around-with-the-tumblr-api.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/angular/api/code/2014/12/17/messing-around-with-the-tumblr-api.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>angular</category>
        
        <category>api</category>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graceul Degradation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My last job was at an agency - pretty standard front-end tasks and projects. We supported IE8+ since we had some pretty big client with thousands of page views a day with half of the traffic mostly coming from IE8 and IE9. Agencies typically prefer to support as many browsers as possible. One client in particular had us support as far back as IE6, though. They had a decent amount of hits coming from outside the US so it made sense. This is the first time I felt that wrath of IE6. Prior to that, my professional career had consisted of IE7+ support. However, while maintaining the website for that particular client, I learned plenty of useful things – but most importantly: &lt;b&gt;graceful degradation&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
During a recent discussion with another web developer, I recalled these moments where I knew a certain feature that IE6 couldn’t handle would not take away from the site or from the overall experience. There are various ways to approach it but mostly you can identify it by just looking at it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&quot;Does not having this break anything on IE9? Does a user still know what is going on?&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to make a little snippet to show a good example of how to go about this. In this example, I use CSS3 (linear-gradient) which is a no-go for IE9. However, IE9 can still display what the user needs to be able to view. It’s a profile completion component - the same idea as LinkedIns’ profile completion. The one on the left has a round progress bar and text beneath it. On the other hand, IE9 doesn’t support linear-gradient so it would just show the text. Using linear-gradient doesn’t break it and the user still has the context needed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;http://jsfiddle.net/sceendy/eoobqufw/embedded/result,js,html,css/&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 10:46:30 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/browser/css3/2014/12/17/graceful-degradation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/browser/css3/2014/12/17/graceful-degradation.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>browser</category>
        
        <category>css3</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day in the Life of a Frontend Developer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me start out by saying that, &lt;strong&gt;yes, I did get this idea from the other frontend dev blogs that I browse&lt;/strong&gt;. I saw a wave of talented front-end web developers blog about what a day in their life is like. It really got me thinking about how we could all be doing the same job (more or less) but manage to have different daily routines. Some developers work remotely daily or once a week, some only work in the office, and there were even some that would cross over between home and the office. From there, some had a lot of meetings, some had none, some had dev team-building events, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the option to work remotely once every two weeks. It&#39;s pretty sweet - I still get to have face-to-face with coworkers but for that one remote day, I can go on a code-binge at home with no distractions. While the office is typically pretty calm, sometimes it&#39;s just nice to be able to get a bunch of tasks done with no interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;A typical remote day...&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my remote days, I&#39;ll go through a few pages of reddit starting at 7:30am. By 8:30am, I will have gotten my daily fix of popular internet things, be showered, and my Keurig will be running. I&#39;ll grab a Cinnabon bagel with my coffee and head to my home office. While I like being distraction-free, I still feel the need to have some kind of sound in the background so I&#39;ll prop up my Chromebook and pull up either Netflix (some random show/episode I&#39;ve seen a million times that could not possibly distract me) or Spotify. Then, I boot up my Macbook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I typically email or message the other developers to let them know I&#39;m working from home first. I also use this time to reply to any emails.  I mean, I am on Google Hangouts if they need me, anyway. So, then, I open up Jira and go through my tasks. I do this for about 10 minutes - responding to comments, updating statuses, and making sure things are ready to test so that the assigner can test the feature and close the task. Once I assess the tasks for the day, I&#39;ll start the code-binge. With a brand-new site, I have &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; to code out whether it&#39;s updated designs (html/scss) or something is broken (angular or API-related)... there&#39;s plenty to do. My boyfriend only works a few minutes away from our house so he comes home for lunch on my remote days. I make lunch at about 12:30pm and eat/chat with him until he heads back at around 1:20pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I get back to my computer and check on the Developer Hangout to see if anything has happened since I was away. I get back to Jira in order to reply to any new comments or check on any new tasks. There might be an email or two waiting for me so I reply to those and get back to coding. If I have a question, I&#39;ll ask the senior UI developer on Hangouts or just head over to &lt;strong&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/strong&gt;. I typically stop working at about 4 on those days. That&#39;s mostly to avoid from having my brain melt if I did not stop... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;At the office...&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into the office means a 10 minute drive followed by a 40 minute train ride. I grab the train before 8:30am and head downtown. While I will occasionally take a Javascript-related book with me... I mostly try to get amped up for work by listening to music. Once I arrive to the office, I grab some coffee, open up Jira, and talk to coworkers. On Mondays we have a developer meeting so that&#39;s typically about a half an hour to an hour long meeting going over development priorities for the week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have design updates to apply, I have the PSD and browser opened up on my second screen and have the Atom editor opened up on my Macbook screen. I like being able to to have the PSD and browser side by side to make sure they match up. Sometimes if there&#39;s no rush, I just set up the html and do the CSS in the browser. I&#39;ll implement the design they created but I also like &lt;em&gt;improving&lt;/em&gt; it so editing the CSS in-browser allows me to show it off. However, typically there isn&#39;t much time to do this so I&#39;ll just write the code, refresh the browser, make sure it matches up with the design, and move to the next task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of coding and organization, we like to start planning for where we are going to lunch with coworkers. Lately I have been opting out of the lunches to be able to sit in the office alone and just review design changes or even try to break the site myself. Post-lunch, I typically start to lighten up and talk more with the fellow devs. At that point, people from other departments walk in to discuss a feature related to their department or to discuss a task in-person either with a backend developer or myself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get another cup of coffee around 3pm... for no other reason than to walk and I really &lt;em&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-heart&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/em&gt; coffee. We have a dev meeting around 3pm on Wednesdays and those are usually a pretty quick
status check on priorities that need to be done by Friday. Then, the other devs and I get back to work and prepare (commit &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-plus&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; push) to do a release to the production site at 4pm. After the release, I start looking at Jira again to see what I can have ready for the next release. Spend a few minutes planning and then back to coding until 5pm. I like to leave at 5pm so that I can catch a not-so-full train at 5:07pm. I arrive to my house at around 6pm which gives me time to cook dinner at a reasonable hour for my boyfriend and I.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 10:26:30 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/working/2014/10/16/day-in-the-life-of-a-frontend-dev.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/working/2014/10/16/day-in-the-life-of-a-frontend-dev.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>working</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New website - using jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you visited the past version of this websites, I&#39;m sure you could tell that I take pride in building my own sites from scratch. My very first website was built using an image map and some &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt;&#39;s thrown together. Ah, to be &lt;em&gt;young&lt;/em&gt;. Once I started learning much more about coding and design, I started building with modern HTML, CSS, and JS. You know, enough to show off my skills since I was still attending UTD with not much of a portfolio yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continued to learn more, I finally decided to build a custom WordPress theme for myself. It was great - from planning, designing, and coding... I loved it. However, after a few months, it seemed like it was bloated for something I barely got to mess around with post-launch. So, a few months ago, I finally decided to &lt;strong&gt;MINIMIZE ALL THE THINGS&lt;/strong&gt;. I redesigned my site again, this time with just simple one-pager for myself that contained information about myself, my projects, and it displayed my tweets. I used things including Angular, Sass, Gulp, and Browserify - hindsight: &lt;em&gt;suuuree&lt;/em&gt;, a bit much for a simple website that had no blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after weeks of being unsatisfied with it... I finally decided to combine my favorite part of WordPress (simple blogging) and my favorite parts of my non-CMS site and that&#39;s where I am now. I installed Jekyll, started designing in browser, and &lt;em&gt;vuala&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I can get on here and write 4 times a month... but don&#39;t hold me to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 10:18:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/jekyll/website/2014/10/15/new.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/jekyll/website/2014/10/15/new.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>website</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Front Porch Frontend Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After months of not going to any kind of developer gathering, I attended the FrontPorch, a frontend web developer conference at the Granada Theater. Among topics covered were some that fairly interested me including Sass (metholodgy), best practices for SVG, deploying with Capistrano, and Node. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img-cutoff&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Check it out, &lt;a href=&quot;http://frontporch.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.frontporch.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 13:18:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sceendy.com/dev/conference/2014/10/08/front-porch-frontend-conference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sceendy.com/dev/conference/2014/10/08/front-porch-frontend-conference.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>dev</category>
        
        <category>conference</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
